<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Keerthi Kodithuwakku</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 05:40:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mind-Controlled Drone and AI for Diabetic Retinopathy Screening</title>
		<link>/mind-controlled-drone-and-ai-for-diabetic-retinopathy-screening/</link>
					<comments>/mind-controlled-drone-and-ai-for-diabetic-retinopathy-screening/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 05:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In addition to Jendo Innovations, Keerthi has launched several other startups. Under these companies (Effective Solutions, Optha Innovations), other innovative [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image alignfull uagb-block-d51690ce wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-full"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/myndrone-320-2.png ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/myndrone-320-2.png 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/11/myndrone-320-2.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/myndrone-320-2.png" alt="" class="uag-image-589" width="469" height="264" title="myndrone-320" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<p></p>



<p>In addition to Jendo Innovations, Keerthi has launched several other startups. Under these companies (Effective Solutions, Optha Innovations), other innovative medical devices and systems are being developed.</p>



<p>One of them is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gClYYkk47A0" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Myndrone</a>, which allows the user to control a drone by using his/her brain waves. “This activity relaxes the brain and the user feels calm after a game session”, Keerthi said.</p>



<p>Another product soon to be launched is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OzzdjogXk2M" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Ophta-AES</a>, a Human Machine Interface (HMI), an AI-powered system to provide early detection of diabetic retinopathy, which is the most common cause of blindness among diabetic patients worldwide.</p>



<p>“Over 45 percent of diabetic patients worldwide develop diabetic retinopathy and most of them could prevent worsening of the disease with early detection”, Keerthi explained</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/mind-controlled-drone-and-ai-for-diabetic-retinopathy-screening/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Jendo: Revolutionizing cardiovascular health monitoring using machine learning</title>
		<link>/introducing-jendo-revolutionizing-cardiovascular-health-monitoring-using-machine-learning/</link>
					<comments>/introducing-jendo-revolutionizing-cardiovascular-health-monitoring-using-machine-learning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 04:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Keerthi Kodithuwakku is a biomedical engineer, the co-founder and CEO of&#160;Jendo Innovations, a bio-medical startup delivering patented healthcare solutions detecting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Keerthi Kodithuwakku is a biomedical engineer, the co-founder and CEO of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.jendoinnovations.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Jendo Innovations</a>, a bio-medical startup delivering patented healthcare solutions detecting abnormalities in the cardiovascular system and seeking to prevent the risk of cardiovascular diseases.</p>



<p>His strong passion for biomedical engineering resisted adverse advice from some senior advisors in the healthcare industry about the lack of prospects in biomedical engineering in Sri Lanka. Along with a like-minded group of engineers, he followed his dream of providing a solution to help solve medical conditions. In their research and entrepreneurial journey, Keerthi said that he found strength and motivation through the strong support of his wife, family, friends, and coworkers in overcoming the obstacles faced when developing Jendo Innovations.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">AI in cardiology – A Steppingstone for Jendo Innovations</h4>



<p></p>



<p>The key developers of Jendo innovations: Keerthi Kodithuwakku, Isuru Rajakaruna, and Charith Vithanage found the most amount of inspiration towards the end of their tenure in undergraduate studies at the University of Moratuwa. This is when they started working on an artificial intelligence-based device identifying abnormalities in the cardiovascular system to predict the risk of disease.</p>



<p>Straight out of university, in 2015, Keerthi co-founded Jendo Innovations with his co-inventors along with Heminda Jayaweera, and Vinod Samarawikrama to commercialize the invention. Keerthi, now 32, said “another motive behind the formation of a registered company was to create a platform and provide opportunities for upcoming biomedical engineers in Sri Lanka to be a part of the Jendo Innovations journey and make good use of their intellectual resources and improve the overall standard of biomedical engineering in the country.”</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardiovascular Diseases: The No.1 Killer in the World</h4>



<p>Cardiovascular Diseases (CVDs) are the leading cause of death worldwide. While managing lifestyles and diets can help reduce the risk of CVDs, understanding the current condition of our blood vessels remains challenging. Existing test procedures are invasive, expensive, and inconvenient, making regular health monitoring difficult.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Endothelial Dysfunction, Disease Tattling</h4>



<div class="wp-block-media-text is-stacked-on-mobile"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="320" height="180" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/blood-vessel-evolution-320-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-579 size-full"/></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<p>Cardiovascular diseases are silent killers, as they often go unnoticed for 20 to 30 years. The progressive worsening of the patient’s conditions goes through multiple stages, from inflammation to the formation of plaque, to the stiffening of walls, ultimately leading to life-threatening blood clots.</p>
</div></div>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">References:</h4>



<p>To learn more about Jendo’s journey and success, check out the following articles:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong><a href="https://www.wipo.int/ipadvantage/en/details.jsp?id=12463">WIPO IP Advantage: Jendo’s Success</a></strong></li>



<li><strong><a href="https://www.wipo.int/meetings/en/details.jsp?meeting_id=72090">WIPO Meetings: Commercialization Process</a></strong></li>
</ol>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/introducing-jendo-revolutionizing-cardiovascular-health-monitoring-using-machine-learning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Healthcare Regulatory Compliance Challenges for Medical Technology</title>
		<link>/introduction-of-jendo-revolutionizing-cardiovascular-health-monitoring/</link>
					<comments>/introduction-of-jendo-revolutionizing-cardiovascular-health-monitoring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 03:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the challenges that the company is facing is finding partners in the health ecosystem. The other one is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One of the challenges that the company is facing is finding partners in the health ecosystem. The other one is going through the health regulatory process as each country has its regulatory authority. Sri Lanka’s regulatory authority is currently reviewing the Jendo system. Once the review is completed, it will allow the commercialization of the device. The company will also apply for the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval, followed by other countries.</p>



<p>Jendo Innovations is also in discussion to establish two business centers outside of Sri Lanka; one in Switzerland, and the other one in Singapore. “Both countries have a favorable business environment, and growth opportunities,” according to Keerthi.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Tried and Tested on Patients to Prevent Heart Disease</h4>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image uagb-block-1e3b9f2a wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-none"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/jendo-medical-device-kit-845.jpg ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/jendo-medical-device-kit-845.jpg 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/11/jendo-medical-device-kit-845.jpg 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/jendo-medical-device-kit-845.jpg" alt="" class="uag-image-572" width="649" height="486" title="jendo-medical-device-kit-845" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<p></p>



<p>Jendo’s system is not commercialized yet but the device is already being used by hospitals and laboratory chains, and clinically tested on over 800 patients.</p>



<p>Under the current business model, the device will be sold at US$2,250 with an annual subscription fee of US$10,000. The test will be charged US$8. According to Keerthi, “the screening price is affordable in comparison with other established procedures.”</p>



<p>The company swiftly proceeded to apply for a patent, first in Sri Lanka (pending), then in the United States (granted:&nbsp;<a href="https://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PALL&amp;p=1&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.htm&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=10,912,464.PN.&amp;OS=PN/10,912,464&amp;RS=PN/10,912,464" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">USPTO Patent 10,912,464 B2</a>), and in Japan (Pending), through the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wipo.int/pct/en/">WIPO Patent Cooperation Treaty</a>&nbsp;(PCT).</p>



<p>According to Keerthi, investors want to make sure the products they invest in is ahead of the competition. “A patent is key to proving the value of your invention and winning investors’ confidence,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/introduction-of-jendo-revolutionizing-cardiovascular-health-monitoring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering Entrepreneurs: Insights from “Business Best” on Building a Thriving Business</title>
		<link>/post-1/</link>
					<comments>/post-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 06:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2024/10/29/post-1/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Key Lessons for Aspiring Entrepreneurs Success Stories: Inspiration from Industry Leaders Actionable Tips and Strategies The Role of Leadership and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Key Lessons for Aspiring Entrepreneurs</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Understanding Market Needs:</strong><br>Entrepreneurs must focus on identifying and addressing the unique needs of their target audience, a concept emphasized repeatedly in &#8220;Business Best.&#8221;</li>



<li><strong>Importance of Adaptability and Innovation:</strong><br>Insights on how businesses can adapt to rapid changes in the market and embrace innovation as a core value.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Success Stories: Inspiration from Industry Leaders</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Profiles of Featured Entrepreneurs:</strong><br>A look at some inspiring guests on &#8220;Business Best,&#8221; detailing how they achieved success and the challenges they overcame.</li>



<li><strong>Real-World Applications of Business Best Practices:</strong><br>Real-life examples of how applying the right strategies can transform business ideas into successful ventures.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong> Actionable Tips and Strategies</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Building a Resilient Business Model:</strong><br>Insights into creating a sustainable business plan, understanding risk, and preparing for economic shifts.</li>



<li><strong>Effective Marketing and Branding Tips:</strong><br>The importance of building a brand identity and connecting with customers through authentic storytelling.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong> The Role of Leadership and Vision in Business Growth</strong></h4>



<p><strong>Setting Goals and Measuring Success:</strong><br>Tips on setting realistic goals and tracking progress to ensure growth aligns with business objectives.</p>



<p><strong>Traits of Successful Business Leaders:</strong><br>From vision to resilience, explore the qualities shared by leaders who make an impact.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/post-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering Voices: How Public Speaking Drives Innovation and Leadership in Business</title>
		<link>/post-2/</link>
					<comments>/post-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 06:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2024/10/29/post-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Power of Public Speaking in Business How Public Speaking Builds Confidence and Credibility Real-World Examples: Leaders Who Transform Through [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Power of Public Speaking in Business</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Effective Communication as a Leadership Skill:</strong><br>Public speaking helps individuals clearly articulate ideas, making it easier for teams to align with a shared vision.</li>



<li><strong>Inspiring Innovation through Storytelling:</strong><br>Storytelling is a powerful tool within public speaking that can turn complex concepts into relatable ideas, sparking creativity and engagement among peers.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong> How Public Speaking Builds Confidence and Credibility</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Establishing Authority and Trust:</strong><br>Speaking in front of an audience boosts credibility, positioning individuals as thought leaders in their field.</li>



<li><strong>Confidence-Building through Practice:</strong><br>Overcoming the challenges of public speaking allows professionals to build resilience and confidence, which translates into more effective communication in all business interactions.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong> Real-World Examples: Leaders Who Transform Through Speech</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Case Study: A Professional’s Journey from Hesitance to Leadership:</strong><br>Share stories of individuals who started with little confidence in public speaking and eventually used it to become prominent business figures or leaders.</li>



<li><strong>Impact of Public Speaking on Business Outcomes:</strong><br>Look at how strong public communication has directly impacted business success, whether in terms of investor relations, team morale, or client acquisition.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Tips to Enhance Your Public Speaking Skills</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Crafting a Memorable Message:</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><br>Tips on structuring speeches to ensure they are concise, impactful, and memorable.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Practice and Feedback:</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><br>Regular practice and seeking feedback can help refine speaking skills, reducing anxiety and improving performance.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Focus on Body Language and Voice Modulation:</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><br>Non-verbal cues play a significant role in engaging the audience. Understanding body language and tone can enhance the impact of a speech.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/post-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Innovation: Jendo Wins the John Keells Open Innovation Challenge 2016</title>
		<link>/post-3/</link>
					<comments>/post-3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 06:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2024/10/29/post-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The John Keells Open Innovation Challenge About Jendo and Their Mission Impacts and Future Prospects for Jendo Inspiring Innovation in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The John Keells Open Innovation Challenge</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Overview</strong>: The John Keells Open Innovation Challenge is one of Sri Lanka&#8217;s premier platforms for fostering innovation and entrepreneurship. It aims to recognize and reward projects that offer novel solutions to pressing challenges in various sectors, including healthcare, technology, and social impact.</li>



<li><strong>Significance of Winning</strong>: Winning this challenge places Jendo among the top innovators in the region. It demonstrates the company’s ability to develop practical solutions with far-reaching impacts on healthcare and wellness.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"> <strong>About Jendo and Their Mission</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Company Vision</strong>: Jendo focuses on harnessing technology to create healthcare solutions that are accessible, effective, and impactful. They aim to address key health challenges through innovations that benefit both medical professionals and patients.</li>



<li><strong>The Winning Project</strong>: Details about the project or product that helped Jendo secure this award. For example, if it was a diagnostic tool or health management app, describe how it works and the problem it solves.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"> <strong>Impacts and Future Prospects for Jendo</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Industry Recognition</strong>: Winning the John Keells Challenge has provided Jendo with not only recognition but also opportunities to grow and collaborate within the industry.</li>



<li><strong>Looking Ahead</strong>: How this win has helped Jendo set new goals, attract investors, or develop future projects. This section can discuss the company’s future plans and how it aims to further impact the healthcare sector.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"> <strong>Inspiring Innovation in Healthcare</strong></h4>



<p><strong>Role in Regional Innovation</strong>: Jendo&#8217;s achievement contributes to the growth of the tech and healthcare sectors in Sri Lanka and beyond. It sets a benchmark for innovation and encourages others to pursue solutions that can make a tangible difference.</p>



<p><strong>Message for Innovators</strong>: The John Keells Open Innovation Challenge and Jendo’s success serve as inspiration for budding entrepreneurs. Their journey emphasizes the importance of determination, creativity, and a solution-driven approach in overcoming healthcare challenges.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image uagb-block-e913a5f8 wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-none"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-3-1024x425-1.jpg ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-3-1024x425-1.jpg 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-3-1024x425-1.jpg 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-3-1024x425-1.jpg" alt="" class="uag-image-562" width="1024" height="425" title="JKX-3-1024x425" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<p></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Finalists with the Executive Board members of John Keells Holdings PLC.</h4>



<p>The JKX Challenge is the first iteration of an initiative by John Keells Holdings to create a conducive ecosystem for young entrepreneurs to create and build bold new ideas. The concept headed by Chairman Susantha Ratnayake is aimed at both helping grow entrepreneurship, but also to encourage businesses at JKH itself to innovate. As a dual-pronged approach, it’s effective. The JKX Challenge partnered with SLASSCOM, ICTA, Ceylon Chamber of Commerce and Roar.lk as their digital media partner.</p>



<p>Mr. Susantha Ratnayake commenting on the Open Innovation Challenge said, “I would like to congratulate the winners and finalists of the inaugural John Keells X Open Innovation Challenge, and I thank all 148 teams that applied from Sri Lanka and overseas, for their enthusiastic participation in the programme.” Mr. Ratnayake further commented, “The JKH leadership is also encouraged by the pool of young entrepreneurial talent we witnessed during the four-month engagement with John Keells X, and we look forward to continuing to support the Sri Lankan startup ecosystem, by incentivising and investing in the talented young entrepreneurs in the country.”</p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image uagb-block-491518ca wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-none"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-2-1024x644-1.jpg ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-2-1024x644-1.jpg 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-2-1024x644-1.jpg 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/JKX-2-1024x644-1.jpg" alt="" class="uag-image-564" width="702" height="440" title="JKX-2-1024x644" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<p></p>



<p>From left: Malaka Rathuvithana (Markify), Gihan Cooray (President of Corporate Finance &amp; Retail Sector, JKH), Susantha Ratnayake (Chairman, JKH), Ronnie Peiris (Group Finance Director), Sohan Dharmaraja (Markify), Ajit Gunewardene (Deputy Chairman, JKH), Dr Hans Wijesuriya (Group CEO – Dialog Axiata PLC), Krishan Balendra (President of Leisure Sector, JKH) and Vinoth Kanna (Markify)</p>



<p>Team&nbsp;<strong>Markify</strong>&nbsp;came in as the runner-up, winning Rs. 1 million for their voice controlled SaaS analytics platform.</p>



<p>Choosing the winners must not have been easy for the judges since each team performed admirably well. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/post-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Start-up Innovation: Highlights from Seedstars Sri Lanka Regional Event</title>
		<link>/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 06:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Seedstars Experience: Supporting Innovation in Emerging Markets Highlights from the Sri Lanka Regional Event The Winning Start-up: Innovation That [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Seedstars Experience: Supporting Innovation in Emerging Markets</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>About Seedstars and Its Global Mission</strong><br>An overview of Seedstars, an organization focused on empowering start-ups in emerging markets, with a specific look at its commitment to fostering innovation in Sri Lanka.</li>



<li><strong>Why Seedstars Matters for Local Start-ups</strong><br>A discussion on how Seedstars helps start-ups connect with resources, mentorship, and a global network, creating pathways to growth and visibility for early-stage businesses.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Highlights from the Sri Lanka Regional Event</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>An Event That Inspires and Empowers</strong><br>Highlights from the day, including inspiring speeches, panel discussions, and networking opportunities that set the stage for a collaborative start-up ecosystem.</li>



<li><strong>Showcasing Sri Lankan Start-ups: A Competitive Spirit</strong><br>A look at some of the competing start-ups and their innovations, demonstrating the diversity and creativity of Sri Lanka’s entrepreneurial scene.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Winning Start-up: Innovation That Stands Out</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Meet the “Best Startup”</strong><br>Introduce the winning team, what they do, and what made them stand out to the judges. Discuss the impact their product or service could have and the significance of winning.</li>



<li><strong>What’s Next: Road to the Seedstars World Summit</strong><br>Details on what lies ahead for the winning team, including their preparation for the Seedstars World Summit in Switzerland, where they will compete with global start-ups.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Building Sri Lanka’s Start-up Ecosystem</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Challenges and Opportunities in Sri Lankan Entrepreneurship</strong><br>An examination of the unique challenges faced by start-ups in Sri Lanka, as well as the growing opportunities for innovation.</li>



<li><strong>Collaborating for a Stronger Future</strong><br>A call to action for increased collaboration among stakeholders—investors, policy makers, and educational institutions—to nurture and support Sri Lankan entrepreneurs.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
